# **Davy Jones**



Senior UI Designer

Portfolio: davyjones.me Email: dmjones.me@gmail.com Mobile: 803-243-4960

Senior UI Designer with 8+ years creating user-friendly web and mobile interfaces. Expert in design systems, high-fidelity prototyping, and user-centered solutions, skilled at turning complex concepts into intuitive, effective designs that meet user needs and business goals. MA in Web Design.

#### **Work Experience**

### Senior UI Designer

Wheels | Aug 2020 - Present

- Spearheaded transition to Figma, lead advanced design sessions and enhance team proficiency.
- Developed and implemented UI components to optimize design and development processes.
- Conducted thorough design system audits, enhancing efficiency/clarity.
- Contributed to visual rebranding efforts for major products, ensuring a cohesive platform experience.

## **UX/UI Designer**

Central Wire | Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

• Authored design governance documentation and led user-centered sessions, enhancing engagement.

## Visual Designer

Palko Services | Nov 2018 - Apr 2019

- Enhanced brand design in publications for improved engagement.
- Conducted A/B testing to optimize content performance.

## **Web Designer**

Oliver Gospel | Oct 2017 – June 2018

• Crafted visually compelling brand and website, boosting organic traffic, and designed custom financial calculators enhancing user interactions.

#### **Web Designer**

Financial Eagle | June 2016 - Aug 2017

• Crafted visually compelling brand and website, boosting organic traffic, and designed custom financial calculators enhancing user interactions.

#### **Education**

### Master of Arts Graphic & Web Design

Minneapolis College Art and Design | 2020 – 2023

## **Bachelor of Science Communications**

Columbia International University | 2012 – 2016

#### **Skills**

- User Interface Design
- User Experience Design
- Wireframing & Prototyping
- User Flow Creation
- Usability Testing
- Visual Design
- Responsive Design
- Mobile App Design

- Web Applications Design
- Design Systems and Guidelines
- Cross-Functional Collaboration
- Design Thinking
- Figma, Sketch, Xd, Invision
- Adobe Creative Suite
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Data Visualization

- · User-centered design
- Accessibility + Inclusive Design
- A/B Testing
- Jira + Agile Methodologies
- Analytical + Problem-Solving
- Communication + Presentation
- Time Management + Organization